<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sports &#8211; Gol Online Mills</title>
	<atom:link href="https://gol.online.mills.edu/category/sports/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://gol.online.mills.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:21:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Khawaja keeps England at bay after Broad strikes in Ashes opener</title>
		<link>https://gol.online.mills.edu/khawaja-keeps-england-at-bay-after-broad-strikes-in-ashes-opener/</link>
					<comments>https://gol.online.mills.edu/khawaja-keeps-england-at-bay-after-broad-strikes-in-ashes-opener/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gol.online.mills.edu/?p=9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Usman Khawaja was in sight of his first hundred in an Ashes match in England as he led an Australia&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Usman Khawaja was in sight of his first hundred in an Ashes match in England as he led an Australia recovery in the first Test at Edgbaston on Saturday.</p>
<p>Australia were struggling at 67-3 after Stuart Broad struck twice in two balls to remove David Warner and Marnus Labuschagne before England captain Ben Stokes captured the prize wicket of star batsman Steve Smith.</p>
<p>But at tea on the second day they were 188-4, with opener Khawaja 84 not out.</p>
<p>That still left Australia 205 runs behind England&#8217;s first-innings 393-8 declared featuring Joe Root&#8217;s 118 not out &#8212; the former captain&#8217;s first Ashes hundred in eight years.<br />
Australia looked as if they might get through the second session without losing a wicket as Khawaja and Travis Head shared a partnership of 81.</p>
<p>Both left-handers went after Moeen Ali, each hitting the recalled off-spinner for sixes in the all-rounder&#8217;s return of 1-82 in 18 overs on his Birmingham home ground.</p>
<p>But Stokes, unlike many a previous England skipper confronted by a spinner conceding runs, kept Moeen, in for the injured Jack Leach, going in what was the bowler&#8217;s first Test in nearly two years since he &#8216;retired&#8217; from all red-ball cricket.</p>
<p>The skipper&#8217;s faith was rewarded when Head, fresh from a hundred in Australia&#8217;s World Test Championship final win over India at The Oval last week, fell for a typically brisk 50 off 63 balls when he dragged a drive off Moeen to Zak Crawley at midwicket.</p>
<p>Australia&#8217;s 148-4 should have become 148-5 when Cameron Green, on a second-ball nought, charged at a sharply-turning Moeen delivery only for wicketkeeper Jonny Bairstow, who made a run-a-ball 78 on Friday, to miss a clear stumping opportunity after snatching at the chance.</p>
<p>Broad had earlier reduced Australia to 29-2 in the seventh over of Saturday&#8217;s play.</p>
<p>During the drawn 2019 Ashes in England, left-handed opener Warner had averaged a meagre 9.50 in 10 innings and was dismissed seven times by the veteran seamer.</p>
<p>And the 36-year-old seamer yet again proved to be Warner&#8217;s nemesis.</p>
<p>Warner had fought hard for a score of nine on an overcast morning favouring England&#8217;s quicks when he chased a wide ball from Broad and inside edged into his stumps.</p>
<p>The roars that greeted Warner&#8217;s exit became deafening next ball when Labuschagne, the world&#8217;s top-ranked Test batsman, fell for a golden duck.</p>
<p>He edged a sharp Broad outswinger that was brilliantly caught one-handed by Bairstow, diving low to his right in front of Root at first slip.</p>
<p>Smith survived the hat-trick delivery but rarely looked comfortable in a 59-ball stay that didn&#8217;t feature a single boundary.</p>
<p>Stokes&#8217;s bowling fitness had been called into question by a longstanding left knee injury, but the lively all-rounder struck when he rapped Smith on the back foot with a nip-back ball.</p>
<p>The batsman&#8217;s review served only to uphold South African umpire Marais Erasmus&#8217;s decision and Smith, whose twin centuries in the Ashes opener at Edgbaston four years ago powered Australia to a 251-run win, was out for 16.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gol.online.mills.edu/khawaja-keeps-england-at-bay-after-broad-strikes-in-ashes-opener/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
