<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Gol Online Mills</title>
	<atom:link href="https://gol.online.mills.edu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://gol.online.mills.edu/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:23:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Oscar-winning UK actress turned MP Glenda Jackson dies at 87: agent</title>
		<link>https://gol.online.mills.edu/oscar-winning-uk-actress-turned-mp-glenda-jackson-dies-at-87-agent/</link>
					<comments>https://gol.online.mills.edu/oscar-winning-uk-actress-turned-mp-glenda-jackson-dies-at-87-agent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gol.online.mills.edu/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[British actress Glenda Jackson, the two-time Oscar-winning actress who went on to become an MP, died on Thursday at the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British actress Glenda Jackson, the two-time Oscar-winning actress who went on to become an MP, died on Thursday at the age of 87, prompting tributes from the worlds of entertainment and politics.</p>
<p>Her agent Lionel Larner said she &#8220;died peacefully at her home in Blackheath London this morning after a brief illness with her family at her side&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;She recently completed filming &#8216;The Great Escaper&#8217; in which she co-starred with Michael Caine,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The film tells the true story of a World War II veteran who escaped his care home to attend a commemoration of the D-Day landings in France.</p>
<p>Caine, who turned 90 this year, described Jackson, with whom he previously worked in 1975 on &#8220;The Romantic Englishwoman&#8221;, as &#8220;one of our greatest movie actresses&#8221;.<br />
&#8220;It was a privilege to work with her on &#8216;The Great Escaper&#8217; recently, our second film together,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was as wonderful an experience this time as it was 50 years ago. I shall miss her.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jackson won the Best Actress Oscar in 1970 for her leading performance in Ken Russell&#8217;s film adaptation of DH Lawrence&#8217;s novel &#8220;Women in Love&#8221;.</p>
<p>She won it again in 1973 for her role in &#8220;A Touch of Class&#8221;, in which she played a woman falling in love with the man with whom she is having an affair.</p>
<p>Despite her status as a formidable actress, she frequently showed her lighter side with appearances on popular British comedy series the &#8220;Morecambe and Wise Show&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8216;Extraordinary talent&#8217;<br />
Jackson was born on 9 May, 1936, in Birkenhead, a small port town near Liverpool, northwest England, to a bricklayer and a cleaning lady.</p>
<p>At 16 she went to work in a chemist&#8217;s shop, doing amateur dramatics in her spare time.</p>
<p>When she was 18 she won a scholarship to the prestigious Royal Academy of Dramatic Art (RADA) in London.</p>
<p>She developed a distinguished career in theatre, which included time with the Royal Shakespeare Company (RSC) working under legendary director Peter Brook.</p>
<p>The Royal Shakespeare Company on Thursday paid tribute to her &#8220;a tour de force in acting and politics, dedicating her life to both&#8221;.<br />
&#8220;We&#8217;re proud her extraordinary talent was seen on RSC stages in her career in ground-breaking productions. Our thoughts are with Glenda&#8217;s family,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>She became a familiar face in cinema from the late 1960s, with Russell championing her early career.</p>
<p>Jackson was elected as a Labour MP for her local London constituency of Hampstead and Highgate in 1992, and served as a transport minister in Tony Blair&#8217;s government between 1997 and 1999.</p>
<p>Jackson stepped down as an MP in 2015, and returned to the stage after an absence of 23 years for a rare gender-swapping role in a London production of ‘King Lear’ in 2016.</p>
<p>A triumphant return<br />
Labour leader Keir Starmer said Jackson&#8217;s death &#8220;leaves a space in our cultural and political life that can never be filled.</p>
<p>&#8220;From award-winning actor to campaigner and activist to Labour MP and government minister, Glenda Jackson was always fighting for human rights and social justice.&#8221;</p>
<p>Alastair Campbell, Labour&#8217;s influential press chief during the Blair government, called her &#8220;one of the finest actresses of our lifetime.</p>
<p>&#8220;I sometimes felt she found the transition to politics harder than she expected. But a great life well lived,&#8221; he tweeted.<br />
Jackson also advised Labour&#8217;s Ken Livingstone when he was London mayor on housing policy and campaigned against homelessness in the capital between 2000 and 2004.</p>
<p>In 2018, aged 82, she won her first Tony &#8212; the equivalent of the Oscars for theatre &#8212; for best actress in &#8220;Three Tall Women&#8221;.</p>
<p>A year later she reprised the role of &#8220;King Lear&#8221; in Broadway for a performance The New York Times described as &#8220;powerful and deeply perceptive&#8221;.</p>
<p>Jackson was married to actor Roy Hodges from 1958 to 1976. Their son Dan Hodges is a political columnist.</p>
<p>In 1978 she was made a Commander of the British Empire by Queen Elizabeth II.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gol.online.mills.edu/oscar-winning-uk-actress-turned-mp-glenda-jackson-dies-at-87-agent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Khawaja keeps England at bay after Broad strikes in Ashes opener</title>
		<link>https://gol.online.mills.edu/khawaja-keeps-england-at-bay-after-broad-strikes-in-ashes-opener/</link>
					<comments>https://gol.online.mills.edu/khawaja-keeps-england-at-bay-after-broad-strikes-in-ashes-opener/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gol.online.mills.edu/?p=9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Usman Khawaja was in sight of his first hundred in an Ashes match in England as he led an Australia&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Usman Khawaja was in sight of his first hundred in an Ashes match in England as he led an Australia recovery in the first Test at Edgbaston on Saturday.</p>
<p>Australia were struggling at 67-3 after Stuart Broad struck twice in two balls to remove David Warner and Marnus Labuschagne before England captain Ben Stokes captured the prize wicket of star batsman Steve Smith.</p>
<p>But at tea on the second day they were 188-4, with opener Khawaja 84 not out.</p>
<p>That still left Australia 205 runs behind England&#8217;s first-innings 393-8 declared featuring Joe Root&#8217;s 118 not out &#8212; the former captain&#8217;s first Ashes hundred in eight years.<br />
Australia looked as if they might get through the second session without losing a wicket as Khawaja and Travis Head shared a partnership of 81.</p>
<p>Both left-handers went after Moeen Ali, each hitting the recalled off-spinner for sixes in the all-rounder&#8217;s return of 1-82 in 18 overs on his Birmingham home ground.</p>
<p>But Stokes, unlike many a previous England skipper confronted by a spinner conceding runs, kept Moeen, in for the injured Jack Leach, going in what was the bowler&#8217;s first Test in nearly two years since he &#8216;retired&#8217; from all red-ball cricket.</p>
<p>The skipper&#8217;s faith was rewarded when Head, fresh from a hundred in Australia&#8217;s World Test Championship final win over India at The Oval last week, fell for a typically brisk 50 off 63 balls when he dragged a drive off Moeen to Zak Crawley at midwicket.</p>
<p>Australia&#8217;s 148-4 should have become 148-5 when Cameron Green, on a second-ball nought, charged at a sharply-turning Moeen delivery only for wicketkeeper Jonny Bairstow, who made a run-a-ball 78 on Friday, to miss a clear stumping opportunity after snatching at the chance.</p>
<p>Broad had earlier reduced Australia to 29-2 in the seventh over of Saturday&#8217;s play.</p>
<p>During the drawn 2019 Ashes in England, left-handed opener Warner had averaged a meagre 9.50 in 10 innings and was dismissed seven times by the veteran seamer.</p>
<p>And the 36-year-old seamer yet again proved to be Warner&#8217;s nemesis.</p>
<p>Warner had fought hard for a score of nine on an overcast morning favouring England&#8217;s quicks when he chased a wide ball from Broad and inside edged into his stumps.</p>
<p>The roars that greeted Warner&#8217;s exit became deafening next ball when Labuschagne, the world&#8217;s top-ranked Test batsman, fell for a golden duck.</p>
<p>He edged a sharp Broad outswinger that was brilliantly caught one-handed by Bairstow, diving low to his right in front of Root at first slip.</p>
<p>Smith survived the hat-trick delivery but rarely looked comfortable in a 59-ball stay that didn&#8217;t feature a single boundary.</p>
<p>Stokes&#8217;s bowling fitness had been called into question by a longstanding left knee injury, but the lively all-rounder struck when he rapped Smith on the back foot with a nip-back ball.</p>
<p>The batsman&#8217;s review served only to uphold South African umpire Marais Erasmus&#8217;s decision and Smith, whose twin centuries in the Ashes opener at Edgbaston four years ago powered Australia to a 251-run win, was out for 16.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gol.online.mills.edu/khawaja-keeps-england-at-bay-after-broad-strikes-in-ashes-opener/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia positions nuclear bombs in Belarus as warning to West</title>
		<link>https://gol.online.mills.edu/russia-positions-nuclear-bombs-in-belarus-as-warning-to-west/</link>
					<comments>https://gol.online.mills.edu/russia-positions-nuclear-bombs-in-belarus-as-warning-to-west/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gol.online.mills.edu/?p=6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Vladimir Putin said on Friday that his deployment of tactical nuclear weapons to Belarus, something he confirmed for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President Vladimir Putin said on Friday that his deployment of tactical nuclear weapons to Belarus, something he confirmed for the first time had already happened, was a reminder to the West that it could not inflict a strategic defeat on Russia.</p>
<p>Speaking at Russia&#8217;s flagship economic forum in St Petersburg, Putin said Russian tactical nuclear warheads had already been delivered to close ally Belarus, but stressed he saw no need for Russia to resort to nuclear weapons for now.</p>
<p>&#8220;As you know we were negotiating with our ally, (Belarusian President (Alexander) Lukashenko, that we would move a part of these tactical nuclear weapons to the territory of Belarus &#8211; this has happened,&#8221; said Putin.</p>
<p>&#8220;The first nuclear warheads were delivered to the territory of Belarus. But only the first ones, the first part. But we will do this job completely by the end of the summer or by the end of the year.&#8221;</p>
<p>The move, Moscow&#8217;s first deployment of such warheads &#8211; shorter-range nuclear weapons that could potentially be used on the battlefield &#8211; outside Russia since the fall of the Soviet Union was intended as a warning to the West about arming and supporting Ukraine, the Russian leader said.</p>
<p>&#8220;&#8230;It is precisely as an element of deterrence so that all those who are thinking about inflicting a strategic defeat on us are not oblivious to this circumstance,&#8221; said Putin, using a diplomatic term for a defeat so severe that Russian power would be diminished on the world stage for decades.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, a staunch ally of Putin, said late on Tuesday his country had started taking delivery of Russian tactical nuclear weapons that included some three times more powerful than the atomic bombs the US dropped on Japan in 1945.</p>
<p>The Russian leader announced in March he had agreed to deploy tactical nuclear weapons in Belarus, pointing to the US deployment of such weapons in a host of European countries over many decades.</p>
<p>Putin says West wants strategic defeat<br />
The United States has criticised Putin&#8217;s decision but has said it has no intention of altering its own stance on strategic nuclear weapons and has not seen any signs that Russia is preparing to use a nuclear weapon.</p>
<p>The Russian step is nonetheless being watched closely by Washington and its allies as well as by China, which has repeatedly cautioned against the use of nuclear weapons in the war in Ukraine.</p>
<p>Putin said the West was doing everything it could to inflict a strategic defeat on Russia in Ukraine where Moscow is locked in the biggest land war in Europe since World War Two after invading its neighbour last year in what it called &#8220;a special military operation.&#8221;</p>
<p>But Russia had no need to resort to nuclear weapons for now, said Putin, signalling no change in Moscow&#8217;s nuclear posture which only envisages such a move if the existence of the Russian state is threatened.</p>
<p>&#8220;Nuclear weapons have been made to ensure our security in the broadest sense of the word and the existence of the Russian state, but we&#8230;have no such need (to use them),&#8221; Putin said.</p>
<p>But he said talks with the West to reduce Russia&#8217;s vast nuclear arsenal, the world&#8217;s largest, were a non-starter.</p>
<p>&#8220;Just talking about this (the potential use of nuclear weapons) lowers the nuclear threshold. We have more than NATO countries and they want to reduce our numbers. Screw them,&#8221; said Putin.</p>
<p>Sounding defiant as he addressed his country&#8217;s political and business elite, he said a Ukrainian counteroffensive against Russian forces in Ukraine had so far not had any meaningful success. Kyiv&#8217;s forces were suffering heavy losses and had &#8220;no chance&#8221; against Russia&#8217;s military, he said.<br />
Ukraine would soon run out of its own military equipment, making it totally reliant on hardware supplied by the West, undermining its ability to fight for long, he suggested.</p>
<p>Recalling his stated objectives at the start of the war to &#8220;demilitarise&#8221; and &#8220;denazify&#8221; Ukraine, Putin said:</p>
<p>&#8220;As for demilitarisation, soon Ukraine will stop using its own equipment altogether. There&#8217;s nothing left. Everything on which they fight and everything that they use is brought in from the outside. Well, you can&#8217;t fight like that for long.&#8221;</p>
<p>Putin gives warning on F-165<br />
Independent military analysts say Ukraine has outperformed Russia&#8217;s much larger army in nearly 16 months of war, forcing it into major retreats around the cities of Kyiv, Kharkiv and Kherson.</p>
<p>Ukraine&#8217;s military chiefs said on Friday that advancing Ukrainian troops were facing &#8220;desperate resistance&#8221; from Russian forces around the city of Bakhmut, which Russia captured last month after the longest battle of the war.</p>
<p>Ukraine says it has recaptured seven villages and 100 square km (38 square miles) in the early stages of its counteroffensive.</p>
<p>But Russia&#8217;s Defence Ministry said on Friday its forces had repelled numerous attempted counterattacks by the Ukrainian army at different frontline locations in the last 24 hours, inflicting severe losses on Kyiv&#8217;s forces.</p>
<p>Putin said Western-supplied hardware such as German-made Leopard tanks was regularly destroyed and if Kyiv got US-made F-16 fighter jets from its allies, they would go up in flames too.</p>
<p>&#8220;F-16s will also be burning, there is no doubt. But if they will be stationed outside Ukraine and used in combat operations we will have to look at how to engage and where to engage those assets being used in combat operations against us.&#8221;</p>
<p>That, he said, represented &#8220;a serious danger&#8221; of dragging NATO further into the conflict.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gol.online.mills.edu/russia-positions-nuclear-bombs-in-belarus-as-warning-to-west/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
