<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Entertainment &#8211; Gol Online Mills</title>
	<atom:link href="https://gol.online.mills.edu/category/entertainment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://gol.online.mills.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:23:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Oscar-winning UK actress turned MP Glenda Jackson dies at 87: agent</title>
		<link>https://gol.online.mills.edu/oscar-winning-uk-actress-turned-mp-glenda-jackson-dies-at-87-agent/</link>
					<comments>https://gol.online.mills.edu/oscar-winning-uk-actress-turned-mp-glenda-jackson-dies-at-87-agent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 17:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gol.online.mills.edu/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[British actress Glenda Jackson, the two-time Oscar-winning actress who went on to become an MP, died on Thursday at the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>British actress Glenda Jackson, the two-time Oscar-winning actress who went on to become an MP, died on Thursday at the age of 87, prompting tributes from the worlds of entertainment and politics.</p>
<p>Her agent Lionel Larner said she &#8220;died peacefully at her home in Blackheath London this morning after a brief illness with her family at her side&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;She recently completed filming &#8216;The Great Escaper&#8217; in which she co-starred with Michael Caine,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>The film tells the true story of a World War II veteran who escaped his care home to attend a commemoration of the D-Day landings in France.</p>
<p>Caine, who turned 90 this year, described Jackson, with whom he previously worked in 1975 on &#8220;The Romantic Englishwoman&#8221;, as &#8220;one of our greatest movie actresses&#8221;.<br />
&#8220;It was a privilege to work with her on &#8216;The Great Escaper&#8217; recently, our second film together,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was as wonderful an experience this time as it was 50 years ago. I shall miss her.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jackson won the Best Actress Oscar in 1970 for her leading performance in Ken Russell&#8217;s film adaptation of DH Lawrence&#8217;s novel &#8220;Women in Love&#8221;.</p>
<p>She won it again in 1973 for her role in &#8220;A Touch of Class&#8221;, in which she played a woman falling in love with the man with whom she is having an affair.</p>
<p>Despite her status as a formidable actress, she frequently showed her lighter side with appearances on popular British comedy series the &#8220;Morecambe and Wise Show&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8216;Extraordinary talent&#8217;<br />
Jackson was born on 9 May, 1936, in Birkenhead, a small port town near Liverpool, northwest England, to a bricklayer and a cleaning lady.</p>
<p>At 16 she went to work in a chemist&#8217;s shop, doing amateur dramatics in her spare time.</p>
<p>When she was 18 she won a scholarship to the prestigious Royal Academy of Dramatic Art (RADA) in London.</p>
<p>She developed a distinguished career in theatre, which included time with the Royal Shakespeare Company (RSC) working under legendary director Peter Brook.</p>
<p>The Royal Shakespeare Company on Thursday paid tribute to her &#8220;a tour de force in acting and politics, dedicating her life to both&#8221;.<br />
&#8220;We&#8217;re proud her extraordinary talent was seen on RSC stages in her career in ground-breaking productions. Our thoughts are with Glenda&#8217;s family,&#8221; it added.</p>
<p>She became a familiar face in cinema from the late 1960s, with Russell championing her early career.</p>
<p>Jackson was elected as a Labour MP for her local London constituency of Hampstead and Highgate in 1992, and served as a transport minister in Tony Blair&#8217;s government between 1997 and 1999.</p>
<p>Jackson stepped down as an MP in 2015, and returned to the stage after an absence of 23 years for a rare gender-swapping role in a London production of ‘King Lear’ in 2016.</p>
<p>A triumphant return<br />
Labour leader Keir Starmer said Jackson&#8217;s death &#8220;leaves a space in our cultural and political life that can never be filled.</p>
<p>&#8220;From award-winning actor to campaigner and activist to Labour MP and government minister, Glenda Jackson was always fighting for human rights and social justice.&#8221;</p>
<p>Alastair Campbell, Labour&#8217;s influential press chief during the Blair government, called her &#8220;one of the finest actresses of our lifetime.</p>
<p>&#8220;I sometimes felt she found the transition to politics harder than she expected. But a great life well lived,&#8221; he tweeted.<br />
Jackson also advised Labour&#8217;s Ken Livingstone when he was London mayor on housing policy and campaigned against homelessness in the capital between 2000 and 2004.</p>
<p>In 2018, aged 82, she won her first Tony &#8212; the equivalent of the Oscars for theatre &#8212; for best actress in &#8220;Three Tall Women&#8221;.</p>
<p>A year later she reprised the role of &#8220;King Lear&#8221; in Broadway for a performance The New York Times described as &#8220;powerful and deeply perceptive&#8221;.</p>
<p>Jackson was married to actor Roy Hodges from 1958 to 1976. Their son Dan Hodges is a political columnist.</p>
<p>In 1978 she was made a Commander of the British Empire by Queen Elizabeth II.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gol.online.mills.edu/oscar-winning-uk-actress-turned-mp-glenda-jackson-dies-at-87-agent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
